Guide to the Waldemar H. Fries Audubon research papers, 1805-1980.
Fries, Waldemar H., Audubon research papers
- Series III. Collateral Files: Sets in America
  - William Home Lizars, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 71)
    Includes a biography, in Auk, October 1908
  - Louisville Talk, December 1967 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Lyceum of Natural History, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - William MacGillivray, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 74)
    Includes an account of his correspondence with John J. Audubon, in Auk, July 1901.
  - The MacMillan Company, 1957-1963 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    Includes a copy of "The Elephant Hunter", Audubon Magazine, September-October 1958.
  - Thomas McCullock, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    Includes transcripts of his correspondence with John J. Audubon, 1835-1840.
  - Regarding the Magazine of Natural History, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Regarding Maria Martin, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    Includes a biography, in the Art Quarterly, Vol XXIII No 3, and articles in the Audubon Magazine, 1963
  - Regarding Joseph Robert Mason, 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Missouri Historical Society, 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Department of Archives and History, Mississippi, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Samuel George Morton, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - National Academy of Design Exhibition Record, 1826-1860. (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Newspapers, 1800s, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 84)
    Includes carbons and transcripts
  - Mrs. Theodore Heyshem, Jr., 1961 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Regarding Thomas Nuttall, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 86)
    Includes a copy of "Audubon and Nutall" in The Scientific Monthly, Vol LXXIV No. 2.
  - George Lehman, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Octavo, 1959-1974 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    Includes sales catalogues and transcripts of John J. Audubon's letters.
  - Ovtavo, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Oil Paintings, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    Includes a list of paintings and "Audubon the Artist", by Edward H. Dwight, and news clippings.
  - Oil Paintings, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    Includes photographs, negatives, illustrations and articles concerning the paintings.
  - Ord-Waterton Correspondence, 1830s and 1840s, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Original Drawings, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    Includes lists, sales catalogues, news clippings, illustrations, 1900s
  - Ornithological Biographies, 1960s, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 94)
    Includes sales catalogues, photgraphs, reviews and transcripts of parts of the book.
  - Ornithologists consulted by Audubon, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Ornithologists or Oologists, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Copies of The Osprey, Dec 1897, April 1898, July 1897, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Dr. George Parkman, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 98)
    Includes a biography in the Harvard Medical Alumni Bulletin, Spring 1962, and an account of his correspondence with Audubon in Auk, April 1916
  - Copy of "Some Philadelphia Ornithological Collections and Collectors, 1785-1850" in Auk, April 1899, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Negatives of Plate #230, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - composite plates, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Portraits, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 102)
    Includes photographs, negatives, illustrations, copies of articles about the portraits, in Auk, 1894, 1955, 1958,
  - Price Lists and Catalogues, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Auction Records (Not Used in The Double Elephant Folio), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Folios - Auctions and Prices, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Prices (Old Print Shop), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 106)
    Includes a copy of a catalogue for 1947
  - Prices (prints), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Prices (Scribner), transcript of a 1940 catalogue, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Prices (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Prices (Reproductions of Double Elephant Folio, Birds of America), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Prices, 1970-1974 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Prices (Kennedy and Company), 1966-1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Copies, prints, photographs and negatives of Catalogues, 1900s (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Prices - Godspeeds, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Prices (Loose and Complete Sets), 1900s (Box 6, Folder 8A)
    Includes negatives, photographs, news clippings and printed catalogues.
  - Auction Prices: Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8B)
  - Regarding Parie du Chien, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Original Cost for Birds of America, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Prints with backgrounds, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Prints (Collection of Loose Prints), 1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Prints (Uncolored), 1960-1965 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Prospectus, 1959-1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Includes a copy of "Note on the birds of America", in Auk April 1916.
  - Prospectus (Institute de France), 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Prospectus, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Includes copies, carbons and photographs of the Prospectus, 1820s-1830s, and reviews, 1800s.
  - Quadrupeds - Prices etc., 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Includes copies of some parts of the book, articles on Audubon's White Wolf, and a copy of the list of subscribers
  - Quadrupeds, 1965-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Reproductions, 1960-1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Includes magazines, brochures, articles and news clippings, 1900s.
  - Reproductions (Chapter), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Reproduction (Textiles), 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Includes negatives, photographs and printed catalogues.
  - The Ariel Press Limited, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Includes news clipping and advertisement poster
  - Johnson Reprint Corporation, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Includes negatives, news clippings and brochures.
  - Reproductions (Chapter), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Herbert Lang and Cie AG, Bern, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Reed and Barton, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - John A Ruthvell, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Requests, 1960-1974 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Regarding Dr. Benjamin Strobel, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Includes a copy of "Strobel's account of Audubon", in Auk 1963, and a biography in Florida Historical Quarterly, January 1963.
  - Reviews of Audubon's Work, 1960s,1970s (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Includes negatives, copies and transcripts of reviews, 1800s.
  - William Roscoe, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - John A Ruthvell, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Regarding Prideaux John Selbey, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    Includes carbons and copies of sales catalogues.
  - Sets Broken Up, 1958-1969 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Sets Destroyed, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Regarding Edward (or Edwin) Sheppard, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Robert Wilson Shufeldt, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    Includes copies of articles by Schufeldt in Auk, October 1866 and 1894.
  - Audubon's Sketchbook, 1960-1972 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Henry Sotheran Limited, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Specimens - Birds of America, 1961-1969 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    Includes copies of articles on birds in the museum of Vassar College, in the American Naturalist, 1871 and Vassar Alumni Magazine, 1944.
  - Isaac Sprague, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 41)
    Includes illustrations of his paintings, in The Month, March 1959 and December 1957.
  - Subscribers, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Original Subscription List: Photographs and Negatives, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Subscribers: Original List, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 44)
    Includes photographs and negatives.
  - Subscribers: Final List (Copies), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Subscribers: Complete and Loose Extant Prints, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Subscribers: Chapters, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Subscribers: Chapter, Original List, Discontinued Subscribers, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Thomas Sully, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 49)
    Includes copies of his correspondence with John J. Audubon, 1824.
  - William Swainson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 50)
    Includes transcripts and accounts of his correspondence with John J. Audubon, 1820s, 1830s.
  - Plate CXIV: Swamp Sparrow, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Synopsis, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Textiles: Reproductions, 1957, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Title Page, Birds of America: Photographs, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Charles Townsend, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 55)
    Includes a copy of "In Audubon's Labrador" by Townsend, in Auk April 1917.
  - John Kirk Townsend, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Regarding James Trudeau, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    Includes a copy of an article describing Trudeau's art, in Tulane Studies in Zoology, April 1962.
  - John Vaughan, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Nicholas Vigors, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Benjamin L. C. Wailes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - John Collins Warren, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Charles Waterton (Box 6, Folder 62)
    Includes copies of his articles on John J. Audubon's work.
  - Regarding the Wernerian Society, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - W. and R. Balston Limited, regarding Whatman Paper, 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Francis Willughby, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 65)
    Includes articles in Auk, July 1925 and October 1940.
  - Alexander Wilson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Alexander Wilson: American Ornithology, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 67)
    Includes copies of the Preface to American Ornithology.
  - Alexander Wilson: List of Subscribers, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Alexander Wilson: Printed Matter, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 69)
    Includes copies of various biographies and pieces on his art, 1900s.
  - Regarding Alexander Wilson, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Emerson Stringham, regarding Alexander Wilson, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - James Wilson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - John Wilson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Regarding the Woodward List, 1901, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 74)
- Series IV. Collateral Files: Sets outside America
  - Germany, 1958-1966 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Staatliche Museen Meiningen, Germany, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - John Galvin, Ireland, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Earl of Caledon, Tyron, Ireland, 1959-1969 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Sig. Luigi Treccani degli Alfieri, Italy, 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Russia, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Darwini Museum, Moscow, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at the museum
  - State Public Library, Leningrad, 1957, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at the library
  - Zoological Institute Academy of Science, Leningrad, 1961-1970 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at the institute
  - Japan, 1958-1972 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    Includes articles on James Biddle and Mathew Perry
  - Biblioteca Nacional, Lisbon, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Baron Krudener, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Sardinia, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - Spain, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - Trinidad, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - The Polish Academy of Sciences, Institute of Zoology, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 111)
    Includes information on Folio prints/plates at the institute
  - University of Aberdeen, Scotland, 1958, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - Duke of Argyll, Scotland, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - Regarding His Grace the Duke of Bedford, England, 1960-1968 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at Woburn Abbey
  - Regarding Barroness Burdett-Coutts, 1969, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 115)
    Includes a biography and copies of catalogues
  - Regarding the Earl of Crawford and Balcarres, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 116)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates held by him
  - Regarding Mary Francis Richardson Currer, 1963-1969 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - Regarding His Grace the Duke of Devonshire, 1960-1974 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at Chatsworth
  - Edinburgh Public Library, 1958-1967 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - Regarding George Head, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - John Heppenstall, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - Regarding the Marchioness of Hertford, 1967-1974 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - Temple Newsman House, Hertford: Photographs, brochures, 1960s (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - Lady Christian Hesketh, 1959-1974 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates held by her
  - Robert W. Oates, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - The Earl of Kinnoull, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 126)
  - Liverpool Public Library, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 127)
  - Liverpool Public Museum, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 128)
  - University of Liverpool, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 129)
    Includes a copy of "Audubon in Liverpool", in the UoL Outlook, 1962.
  - The Mitchell Library, Glasgow, 1958-1972 (Box 8, Folder 130)
    Includes a biography of Robert Jeffrey, and a list of Folio prints/plates at the library
  - Central Library, Manchester, 1959-1972 (Box 8, Folder 131)
  - The Countess of Morton, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 132)
    Includes a copy of an article in Auk, April 1926.
  - The Natural History Society of Northumberland, Durham and Newcastle upon Tyne, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 133)
  - His Grace the Duke of Portland, 1959-1972 (Box 8, Folder 134)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates at Welbeck Abbey
  - University of Newcastle upon Tyne, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 135)
    Includes exhibition catalogues, 1966
  - Queens College, Oxford University, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Paisley Central Library, 1958-1969 (Box 8, Folder 137)
  - Lord Pembroke, Earl of Salisbury, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 138)
  - N. M. Rothschild, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 139)
  - Comptroller to H. R. H. Princess Royal, Leeds, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 140)
  - John Rhylands Library, Manchester, 1959-1968 (Box 8, Folder 141)
  - Royal Faculty of Physicians and Surgeons, Glasgow, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 142)
    Includes a list of Folio prints/plates by the faculty
  - Victoria and Albert Museum, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 143)
  - The Royal Library, Windsor Castle, 1961-1967 (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - University of St. Andrews, Scotland, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 145)
  - National Library of Scotland, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 146)
  - Sandeman Public Library, Perth, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 147)
  - Royal Scottish Museum, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 148)
- Series V. Correspondence and Notes after 1973
  - Audubon Watercolours and Wallpapers, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Includes illustrations of wallpaper prints and watercolors
  - Audubon Weekend, Bethany College, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Includes photographs, brochures and invitations
  - Peabody Museum, Yale University Art Gallery, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - David M. Lank, May 1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Unknown Dealer" of the set at Darlington Library, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - New York Society Library, March 1975 - April 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Set at Library of New South Wales, Sydney, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Thomas McCulloch House, October 1974 - November 1974 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Louis Fuertes' Letter to Prof. Herrick, 1918, October 1974 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Gaye Graves Crannell: Master's Thesis, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - E. R. Eller: Alleged Audubon Drawing, April 1975 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Regarding Bien Chromolithograph Prints, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "Audubon in Ohio", in the Enquirer Magazine, 20 April 1975 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Audubon Magazine, November 1974 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Includes a copy of the magazine, January 1888
  - Mitchell A. Wilder: "Audubon China", April 1975 - May 1975 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Regarding books, magazines and paintings relating to John J. Audubon, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Includes sale sheets, brochures and newspaper clippings
  - Christie, Mason and Woods, 1975-1980 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Copy of the UCLA Librarian, October 1980 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - A. B. Bookman Weekly, April 1976 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Audubon Folio Conservation: Carolyn Horton and Associates, July 1978 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Ann Lee Morgan: Audubon Folio - Bein Edition, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    Includes a copy of "American Audubons: Julius Bien's Lithographed Edition" by her
  - Mitchell Wolfson: Theft at Audubon House, Key West, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Includes original and copies of newspaper clippings
  - Audubon - Miscellaneous, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    Includes brochures, newspaper clippings, horoscope and articles ("Audubon's 'View of Baltimore'", "John James Audubon and his Charleston Physician Friends")
  - Mrs. henry A. Morss, Jr., 1975 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Audubon Wildlife Sanctuary: Rare Art Theft, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Bien Editions: Exhibitions and Requests for Information, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    Includes catalogues and brochures
  - Bethany College, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Marc Bielenberg, April 1976 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Gordon S. Braislin, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Art Theft: Boston Public Library, 29 July 1980 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Charleston Society Library, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - The City College, New York City, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Copper Plates, September 1975 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Corrections and Additions, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    Includes copies of "How the Young Men's Association Got its Audubon and Why they Didn't Get All of It - A Hypothesis" and supporting material.
  - Regarding Mrs. Virginia (Samuel Hancock) duPont's Set, 1975-1978 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Free Public Library, City of New Bedford, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Groton School, December 1980 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Haverford College, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    Includes transcripts of John. J Audubon's correspondence
  - Japan, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Robert D. Jameson, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Regarding Mrs. Grace Philips Johnson, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    Includes a list of letters held by her heirs, and a description of the Grace Phillips Johnson Collection at Bethany College
  - Paul F. Laning, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - David M. Lank, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    Includes negatives, photographs and transcripts of John J. Audubon's correspondence, 1840
  - "Audubon's View of Baltimore" by George E. Gifford and Florence B. Smallwood, Maryland Historical Magazine, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence: D,E,F, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Louisiana State University Library, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    Includes brochures, newspaper clippings, and multiple copies of Umieres, published by Friends of the Library (Louisiana State University).
  - Thomas McCulloch, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 56)
    Includes photographs and negatives of Chromolithograph prints.
  - Milwaukee Public Library, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    Includes newspaper clippings
  - "Audubon and Bonson: Two trends in American Bird Prints" by Elisabeth W. Mixter, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Museum National d'Histoire Naturelle, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - National Gallery of Art, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - The New York Society Library, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Regarding the set at Northwestern University, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Notes on birds in the Octavo Edition, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Mrs. Gilbert W. Paul, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Peabody Institute Library, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Philbrook Art Center, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Prints, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Prices, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    Includes Price Lists, Brochures and Catalogues
  - Quadrupeds, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - R. K. Smith, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Smithsonian Institute, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Notes on Isaac Sprague, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Stark Foundation Museum of Art, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - State Library of new South Wales, Sydney, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Weidenfield and Nicholson, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Ms Lucinda Kirk Vistain, 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Volair limited, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    Includes brochures and catalogues
  - Micheal Zinman, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - "Ornithological Illustration" by W. B. Alexander, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 79)
- Series VI. Notebooks: Copies of Audubon Letters and Journals, Photographs, Negatives and other Auduboniana
  - Time-line of Audubon's life: June 1824 - December 1831 (Box 11)
  - Time-line of Audubon's life: January 1832 - June 1839 (Box 11)
  - Time-line of Audubon's life: July 1839 - November 1846 (Box 11)
  - Photographs: Original Subscription List (Box 11)
    Includes the type of cover (or case) used by Audubon to hold subscribers list, photographs of the panel in which subscriber's names are presently framed and photographs of subscription lists from Ornithological Biographies
  - Photographs: Legends and plates of the Double Elephant Folio Birds of America at the Providence Athenaeum (Box 11)
  - Photographs: Audubon's work housed at libraries, museums and private collections (Box 11)
  - Negatives and photographs (Box 11)
    Negatives: Copy of First Prospectus
    Negatives: Legends - Plate 64 (Swamp Sparrow) and others
    Negatives: Plates from Audubon Books
    Negatives: Original Subscription list - from His Most Gracious Majesty George IV to Richard Harlan; Auk, Vol III October 1886, No. 4, "On an old portrait of Audubon, painted by himself - and, a word about some of his early Drawings"
    Negatives: Audubon's Ledger showing Astor and Lenox fragments
    Negatives: First ten plates, British Museum
    Photographs and Negatives: Yellow Billed Cuckoos, Black Billed Cuckoos
    Photographs: Plate 22 Yellow Billed Cuckoo, showing erasure, from the American Museum of Natural History, NY
    Photographs: Legend of the folio at Brown University
    Photographs: Auk, Vol III October 1886, No. 4, "On an old portrait of Audubon, painted by himself - and, a word about some of his early Drawings"
    Photographs: Folios from the British Museum
    Photographs: Reproductions of Copper Plate #277 (Hutchin's Goose), American Museum of Natural History, NY
    Photographs: Plate 64 variations; Plate 10 variations
    Photographs: Variations of Plate 64 (Swamp Sparrow)
  - Notes, lists and transcripts of Birds of America and Audubon's correspondence and journals (Box 11)
    Audubon Letters - BAu-25 and oversize, American Philosophical Society, PA
    Audubon Letters - in odd volumes of Letters of J.J.A, American Philosophical Society, PA
    List of contents, Ledger B, Birds of America - Audubon Memorial Museum
    Extracts from Audubon's Journal - Houghton Library, Harvard University
  - Notes, lists and transcripts of Audubon's correspondence kept at Houghton Library, Harvard University (Box 11)
  - Notes, lists and transcripts of Audubon's journals and correspondence (Box 11)
    Audubon's Journals (8) - Houghton Library, Harvard
    Audubon Letters - Lownes, Providence, RI
    Audubon Letters - Museum - Henderson, Kentucky
    Audubon Letters - Mrs. Grave Phillips Johnson, New Castle, PA
    Audubon Letters - Miscellaneous and chronological
    Letters of Introduction (Copies) - Buffalo Society, NH
  - Detailed Notes: Audubon's Original Paintings at the New York Historical Society (Box 11)
  - The 1956 Bird Calendar, Grant Hill Publishing Co. (Box 9)
  - Copies of Audubon letters, 1805-1831 (Box 9)
  - Copies of Audubon letters and other material, 1826-1844 (Box 9)
  - Photographs and other material submitted to American Library Association (Box 9)
  - Photographs and other material submitted to American Library Association (Box 9)
  - Photographs and other material submitted to American Library Association (Box 9)
- Series VII. Audubon Material
  - Audubon's Story of his Youth, in Schubner's Magazine, March 1893 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Audubon's Style of Drawing Birds, in the Edinburgh Journal of Science and Audubon and his Journals., January 1828, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - John Woodhouse Audubon, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Lucy Audubon, 1963-1866, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Victor Gifford Audubon, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Audubon and Alexander Wilson, in The Wilson Bulletin., March 1908 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Reminiscences of John James Audubon, in The Louisiana Historical Society Bulletin, November 1910 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - A Visit to Audubon's Birthplace, by O Widmann. (Box 4, Folder 23)